<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<series
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="file:///C:/xampp/htdocs/proyecto/series/series.xsd">
    <serie id="1">
        <name>Devs</name>
        <title>Alex Garland Wants to Break Your Brain with the Brilliant Devs</title>
        <image> 
            https://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/blog_post/primary_image/streaming/alex-garland-wants-to-break-your-brain-with-the-brilliant-devs/01_Sonoya_Actor_spread_re.01_copy.jpg
        </image>
        <review>The genius behind “Ex Machina” and “Annihilation” brings his brand of highly philosophical and intellectual sci-fi to the new ‘FX on Hulu’ section this week with the stunningly ambitious “Devs,” a great show that’s almost impossible to write about in a review. Like he did in his last two films, Alex Garland unpacks his themes slowly and deliberately, not revealing what “Devs” is primarily about until several episodes in. Not only do we not have a habit on this site of spoiling anything major that happens after a series premiere, but FX has been insistent about not revealing what this show really becomes. All I’ll say is that it’s a daring and new deconstruction of one of the basic tenets of human existence. At times throughout the season, Garland’s tendency to direct actors to affectless, almost monotonous performances will push casual viewers away, but I plead patience here. It’s ultimately an unforgettable and rewarding experience, and one that I really hope people are talking about and writing about once everything has been put on the table.
            Lily Chan (Sonoya Mizuno, who was Oscar Isaac’s dance partner in “Ex Machina”) is a software engineer at a company called Amaya, run by the mysterious Forest (Nick Offerman). Amaya is like any number of Silicon Valley companies trying to do something that the rest of the competition in the tech sector isn’t even considering. There’s an elite branch of Amaya called “Devs,” and Lily’s boyfriend Sergei (Karl Glusman) is basically promoted to that exclusive department in the premiere. He goes to work in Devs, meeting fellow elites like the mysterious Katie (Alison Pill) and kindly Stewart (Stephen McKinley Henderson), but only after a serious grilling by security head Kenton (Zach Grenier). After his first day in Devs, Sergei disappears, and the show becomes Lily’s story, trying to figure out what exactly happened to her boyfriend and how it's related to what they do in Devs.
            We know the answer to the first question when it happens but the exact nature of the tech research in Devs unfolds slowly, dominating the mystery of the first half of the season. And it does so in a manner that feels more like a ‘70s conspiracy thriller than a traditional sci-fi film. There are covert meetings with dangerous people under bridges and in parking garages, and bursts of shocking violence in “Devs.” Garland has a storytelling model and Lily is cut from the same cloth as Domhnall Gleeson’s character in “Ex Machina” and Natalie Portman’s in “Annihilation,” the observer who then changes what’s being observed. He’s fascinated by human interaction with technology but not in a cold, observant way. There’s a push and pull between individuality and determinism in all of his work, and he digs deep into how systems are shaped by human input, need, and emotion.

            Clearly, there’s a lot to chew on in “Devs,” but some of the performances can feel a bit overly familiar. Offerman gets better but starts the season as a bit of a tech messiah archetype that we’ve seen before. He’s a character meant to hold so many secrets as to his purpose in the first few episodes that his mysterious nature almost tends to parody. Similarly, Mizuno feels like a blank slate early in the season but she’s asked to do a lot in the back half of the year and she ultimately worked for me. What I liked most about the cast of “Devs” is how much Garland chose to work with a very tight ensemble. A lot of creators think high-concept TV means dozens of arcs, subplots, and speaking roles—“Westworld” often fell victim to this—but “Devs” is comparatively focused, allowing Garland, who wrote and directed every episode, to really sketch out each of his speaking roles into interesting characters.
            “Devs” also simply looks better than most modern television, shot by Garland’s regular collaborator Rob Hardy. Working with Garland, they give the show a much warmer, denser color palette than it would have had in other hands. Even the production design of the Devs building fascinated me with its undeniably futuristic look that is also balanced by warm colors, which makes more sense when one learns Forest’s grand plan. It’s that kind of show, one in which design and visual choices were clearly influenced by theme and plot instead of merely functional. It’s a show that’s as constantly surprising in its artistic choices—for example, how an early fight scene is staged is startling—as it is in its narrative. It feels constantly just left-of-center, even when it’s treading familiar sci-fi ground.

            There’s a scene late in the season in which Forest mentions how every generation seems to be speeding up development. For generations, we were happy in caves, painting on the walls. Now, there’s a new way to communicate and comprehend the world every few hours. Alex Garland wants to question and confront what this acceleration means for the human race. And he’s done so with one of the best new shows in a long time.

        </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="2">
        <name>Little Fires Everywhere</name>
        <title>'Little Fires Everywhere' Finds Families Ready To Collide</title>
        <image> 
            https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/03/17/littlefires_wide-4f523b60da8810925da3252cc120b1f56b38bff6-s1600-c85.jpg
        </image>
        <review>The great frustration of Little Fires Everywhere, the Hulu adaptation of Celeste Ng's popular novel, is that of the eight episodes, they only made seven available for review.

            It matters because Little Fires Everywhere is a story of collision. Mia (Kerry Washington) and her daughter Pearl (Lexi Underwood), temporarily living in their car, come to Shaker Heights, Ohio. They collide with the wealthy Elena Richardson (Reese Witherspoon), who has a house to rent. Mia and Pearl become entangled with Elena and her husband and four children, and eventually, even their friends can't avoid each other.
            
            Those who have seen Big Little Lies will recognize Elena as a more malevolent version of the wealthy, driven, status-obsessed mother Witherspoon she plays there. Ohio and not Monterey, and yet recognizably similar. Those who have seen Scandal may even recognize Mia as a much less well-connected version of the driven survivor Washington plays there. Putting the very different energies of these actresses in conversation with each other is a good, promising idea.

            Much of the story also takes place in the complex emotional lives of Elena and Mia's children. In particular, Mia worries over the attachment Pearl quickly forms to the Richardsons, and to their nice big house and their leisure time and their stability. Elena is baffled by her youngest, a budding artist and raw nerve named Izzy (Megan Stott), who gravitates toward Mia, both because she's an artist and because she's almost as skeptical of Elena as Izzy is.

The series doesn't quite feel solid, in part because as it progresses, Elena becomes more unambiguously awful. It's a better show when it feels like two very different mothers with very different cards to play, trying in their own ways to offer the parenting they think is needed. But a plot development involving a co-worker of Mia's and a friend of Elena's winds up unbalancing their relationship. While this creates a certain tension, it's hard to know whether that tension will find any resolution.

But again, this is the frustration: The point is that the first seven episodes build and build the pressure on and among all these characters and the worlds they inhabit. Pearl and Izzy feel rejected by their mothers; Elena and Mia feel pushed away by their daughters. Elena's other daughter Lexi is pushed to confront her own privilege, while her brothers Trip and Moody have different attachments to Pearl and different ways of treating her well and poorly. It builds and builds, and either the series sticks the landing in that last episode and it feels worth the ride, or it doesn't, and it doesn't.

With some series, this feels less important. In some cases, the pleasures of a show are such that there's less of a nagging concern over whether it will successfully tie itself together. But this one feels just unsteady enough that if it doesn't land on a coherent final chord, it won't hold together as a whole. The caliber of performers and the strength of the source material makes me optimistic. But in a series about collision, not getting to see what happens when everything collides makes it hard to feel like you've seen it at all.

        </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="3">
        <name>Dark</name>
        <title>5 Reasons Why You Should Be Watching ‘Dark,’ Netflix’s New Twisty German Time Travel Show</title>
        <image> 
            https://www.thewrap.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/netflix-dark-time-travel-show-why-you-should-watch.jpg 
        </image>
        <review>  In the era of peak TV, it often feels next to impossible to actually keep up with the shows you
            already watch, much less try to start new ones. I get it. I watch TV for a living and even I
            can’t keep up with as many shows as I would like.

            So with that in mind, I’m gonna pitch you on “Dark,” the extremely heady new time travel show
            that just landed on Netflix. It’s going a bit under the radar right now, sandwiched between “The
            Punisher” and the second season of “The Crown.” Also it’s in German rather than English, which
            may put you off. But having watched its 10-episode first season twice now, I can confirm it’s
            worth your time.

            “Dark” takes us to the small town of Winden, Germany, a place full of fun personal melodrama —
            and also children who have gone missing without a trace. It centers on a handful of families
            that have lived there for a long time and are prominent in the community. The time travel
            conceit does more than give us a window into how these families have evolved over many decades —
            it’s brings a whole new meaning to “things are not quite what they seem here.”
            I’m going to stop there with the description. I’m not usually one to be overly concerned
                about spoilers, but “Dark” is such a weird and twisty thing that It’s tough to talk about it
                much without delving into a place that even I would call spoiler territory. “Dark” is a show
                best discovered with the bare minimum of information about its premise. That being said, I’m
                going to, without spoilers, explain why I like the show below, if you need more
                encouragement.

          1. It’s a little bit “Stranger Things,” a little bit “Twin Peaks,” a little bit “Lost” and a
                whole bunch of doing its own thing

                “Dark” is the kind of show where, early on before you really get to know it, you can feel
                the vibes of shows that came before. The stories that influenced “Dark” are ones that deal
                with people who are wrestling with extra-natural forces that are just beyond their
                understanding. But it’s certainly not a show that wears those influences on its sleeve —
                series creators Baran bo Odar and Jantje Friese have crafted a fiercely original piece of
                fiction that is one of the most thoughtful and unique TV shows of 2017.

           2. It’s one of the rare on-screen time travel stories with airtight time travel logic

                Time travel is hard, OK. It’s inherently illogical and can’t follow the rules of reality as
                we know them in the real world. So the foundation of any good time travel story has to be
                the rules. You can set whatever time travel rules you want, so long as you stick with them —
                if you don’t, the story falls apart. It’s a whole extra thing the writers of a story have to
                deal with, in addition to simply trying to write a good story in the usual sense. So it’s
                easy to mess that up, because it requires basically double the work.
                2. It’s one of the rare on-screen time travel stories with airtight time travel logic

                Time travel is hard, OK. It’s inherently illogical and can’t follow the rules of reality as
                we know them in the real world. So the foundation of any good time travel story has to be
                the rules. You can set whatever time travel rules you want, so long as you stick with them —
                if you don’t, the story falls apart. It’s a whole extra thing the writers of a story have to
                deal with, in addition to simply trying to write a good story in the usual sense. So it’s
                easy to mess that up, because it requires basically double the work.

         
                3. It’s also a super compelling personal drama

                There’s one major character, Ulrich (Oliver Masucci), who I’ve been really fascinated by
                since I watched the series. “Dark” puts Ulrich at the center of things for a while, and
                successfully made me care about him even though he’s really kind of a terrible and not
                particularly likable person the whole way through. What makes him work as a character is how
                truly human he feels, and Ulrich is representative of how Odar and Friese treat all their
                characters. There isn’t a single major character on “Dark” who you can’t empathize with on
                some level, which makes all their myriad interactions and conflicts all the more engrossing.


                4. It uses time travel as a religious metaphor

                Without delving into the particulars, “Dark” takes a sort of existential angle with its time
                travel shenanigans, with characters talking about time as if it were God — and who talk
                about time travel is if it were a means to exert power over God. It’s a fascinatingly weird
                angle for a time travel story, and one that worked like gangbusters on me since I come from
                an extremely religious part of the U.S. That Friese and Odar would even think to take the
                story this way is demonstrative of how “Dark” goes to places you find anywhere else in the
                realm of television this year.

 
                5. It’s just extremely cool looking, with a stellar score to boot

                Aside from simply being an excellent show, “Dark” also manages to be one of the more
                visually striking shows around. It’s up there, in fact, with “Westworld,” the new “Twin
                Peaks,” and “Hannibal.” And it’s got a score to match, simple and booming and dread-fueled.
                “Dark” would probably still be very good were these elements not working on this level, but
                that they do elevates the show into a truly complete package.


        </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="4">
        <name>Manifest</name>
        <title>Think “Lost,” but without an island, a smoke monster or donkey wheel.</title>
        <image>
            https://pmcvariety.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/manifest.jpg
        </image>
        <review>
            Flight delays are all too frequent for today’s travelers. It’s bad enough being sardined into a
                        coach seat in a virus-spreading tube full of fellow humanoids.

                        NBC’s Manifest, premiering Monday, Sept. 24th at 9 p.m. (central) following the latest restart
                        of The Voice, offers the mother of all late arrivals. After taking off from Montego Bay, Jamaica
                        on April 7, 2013, Montego Airways Flight 828 finally touches down in New York on Nov. 4, 2018.
                        Talk about missing your connecting flight. And holy Trump presidency! But that’s not referenced
                        in the pilot episode, which is all that NBC made available for review.

                        &#xD; A total of 191 passengers are on board. And they’re treated to some brief, but heavy
                        in-flight turbulence, with the plane shaking, rattling, rolling while the lights go out and
                        everybody has a good yell or scream. The friendly captain then references a severe weather
                        disturbance that for whatever reason didn’t show up on the radar. And now back to your movie.

                        &#13;&#10; The Stone family initially is at center stage. Ben (Josh Dallas), his leukemia-afflicted
                        son, Cal (Jack Messina), and his troubled sister, Michaela Beth (Melissa Roxburgh), elect to
                        jettison their overbooked flight and take a later one in return for $400 vouchers. Ben’s wife,
                        Grace (Athena Karkanis), their daughter, Olive (Luna Blaise) and her grandma and grandpa take
                        the earlier plane, which arrives as scheduled.

                        &#13;&#10; 
                        So what happened beyond everybody else getting five-and-a-half years older while the FL
                        191 crew and passengers stayed as is and now are starting to hear voices in their heads?

                        &#xD;  Episode One is well-made and poses many more questions than answers. But you know the
                        drill. What if the ratings crash-land and NBC in turns grounds Manifest without ever resolving
                        much of anything? There goes your investment in a manner befitting a Ponzi scheme. Life is so
                        much simpler when you can just binge an entire season of episodes on a streaming site rather
                        than hoping a broadcast will keep doling them out.

                        Michaela, who’s also a cop, had been urged by her parents and brother to go ahead and marry
                        detective Jared Vasquez (J. R. Ramirez). But she was still having issues at the time. And now
                        that she’s ready to take the plunge, he’s grown older, had given Michaela up for dead and has
                        moved on. Ben’s wife also has a little somethin’ somethin’ goin’ on, but the particulars are
                        still awaiting a future episode.

                        Roxburgh is effective in the lead role while her co-stars (including Parveen Kaur as a medical
                        researcher named Saanvi) so far are making lesser impressions. The first episode ends with
                        Michaela’s narrative advisory that “this was just the beginning.”

                        &#xD; &#xA; Viewers have heard variations on this before, only to be strung along and then jilted by a
                        cancellation that left just about everything hanging. Even so, Manifest is worth a look, with
                        the proviso that the only way it will last is if enough people see reasons to keep watching.
                     </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="5">
        <name>How to Get Away with Murder</name>
        <title>Isn't conceptually original, but it delivers thrills with melodramatic twists and a captivating lead.</title>
        <image>
            https://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/blog_post/primary_image/streaming/tv-review-abcs-how-to-get-away-with-murder-and-black-ish/136348_GROUPr4_pre.jpg
        </image>
        <review>Far less essential but still entertaining is the next night’s “How to Get Away with Murder,” starring the always-fantastic Viola Davis as Professor Annalise Keating, the kind of Criminal Law teacher who apologizes to her students for the mistakes they must have made to get stuck in the toughest class in school. Keating is driven to the point of abuse, insulting the intelligence of her students on day one, trying to put pressure on her kids to weed out the ones who couldn’t make it in a courtroom. She even has them work an active case before opening a book, forcing them each to come up with a unique defense for her client. The best arguments win positions at her law firm. But each one has to be different. The point is clear: it's not about the law, but the most creative way to defend your client.

            Candidates for the job include the wide-eyed but naïve Wes Gibbins (Alfred Enoch), confident Michaela Pratt (Aja Naomi King), tricky Connor Walsh (Jack Falahee), quiet Laurel (Karla Souza) and snobby Asher (Matt McGorry). They work with two of Keating’s assistants: Frank (Charlie Weber) and Bonnie (Liza Weil). It’s a lot of names and faces to introduce an audience to in episode one, and the clutter is enhanced by the fact that we learn that Annalise’s best and brightest eventually get involved in something murderous of their own. The premiere opens with the students trying to hide a body, flashing back to their first day in Keating’s class along the way. Did Annalise really teach her students “How to Get Away with Murder”? It’s hard to say how long this structure will last. Will we jump forward next week or will the show take place in two timelines all season? And then shoving an actual mystery-of-the-week in there too? “How to Get Away with Murder” is a crowded show, a fact that the producers try to discuss by editing like a music video. This thing flies, with more cuts than your average sports broadcast. I’ll say that I watched it twice (an original, less-hyper version and the revised one) and it felt much shorter than its running time both times. However, it’s a show that needs to slow down and catch its breath soon or viewers will be more exhausted than entertained.
            
            I’m also hoping it slows down long enough for Davis to shine. She has a few beats here that feel overcooked—her classroom introductory scene is so far over-the-top that it shatters belief—but she already shows signs of the well-rounded character I expect she’ll develop, especially in the quieter beats, such as after a student catches her in an intimate moment. Davis is such a phenomenal actress that it’s tempting and easy to say that she’s better than the material she’s given here, but hopefully she can elevate the show around to her level. She does so often enough in the premiere that I’m willing to see if she can keep it up.

        </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="6">
        <name>You</name>
        <title>What would you do for love?</title>
        <image>
            https://www.newstatesman.com/sites/default/files/styles/cropped_article_image/public/blogs_2019/01/you_101_08292017_jm_1287.jpeg?itok=izwmvBeG
        </image>
        <review>Joe Goldberg will happily commit federal crimes and betray his closest friends to get what he wants, but he wouldn’t let that stop him from feeling morally superior to everyone he knows. An educated, literary New Yorker who works in a deliberately shabby bookshop, he obsessively stalks a one-time customer, Beck (Elizabeth Lail), manipulating her into becoming his girlfriend, before picking off her friends one by one, to ensure her never competes for her attention. But those friends are rich, hyper-privileged, narcissistic, attention-seeking personality vacuums – so what jury would convict him?

            As a pulpy crime thriller, the Netflix series You does what it says on the tin – offering surprise twists, drip-fed reveals, a magnetic villain in Joe (Gossip Girl’s Penn Badgley), the horrible suspense of knowing more than his clueless victims, and satisfyingly gory murders (well, at least 50 per cent of the time – while men are poisoned, stabbed and pushed off buildings before our eyes, all the violence against women happens off screen). But its sparklingly cruel sense of humour is what makes it compulsively watchable – through Joe’s sardonic narration (always addressed to Beck), the show displays a rare eagerness to ridicule its own characters.
            Take Benji, Beck’s ex, a boarding school-bred, constantly partying sexist. He is the CEO of artisanal beverage company, lies about having read On The Road, and is, in Joe’s words, “a waste of hair”. Or Peach Salinger (Shay Mitchell), the orthorexic heiress to a seemingly infinite JD Salinger fortune, who splits her time between IV vitamin treatments, geothermal mud masks and cutting down her friends. “I can’t have any fast food,” she whines. “And if I drink, it has to be a high PH, you know, like Ketel One or Goose and pear juice.”
            There’s the casually racist Annika, and Lynn, “a dark cavern where conversations go to die”. There’s the literary agent trying to seduce young writers with coke in the back of his limo. (“He’s been clean since 9/11!” a friend protests. “When it happened, he was in an airport!”) Hari Nef gives a winning performance as the incredibly annoying yet somehow fundamentally likable Blythe, a supposedly brilliant writer who says things like, “Sorry I’m late, there was this essay in the Believer that would not let go of me,” and “Percival, back from the ashram? Tell me everything!”
            
        </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="7">
        <name>Scandal</name>
        <title>‘Scandal’ recap: ‘White Hat’s Back On’ for Olivia, but what of the gladiators?</title>
        <image>
            https://pyxis.nymag.com/v1/imgs/23c/799/395937eb189bf61b8ae090b16a77f076fa-19-scandal-season-2.rhorizontal.w700.jpg
        </image>
        <review>I may need to lie down. The season finale of “Scandal” was so packed with ups and downs and twists and turns I may be a little sick to my stomach. Some story lines were tied up with a neat little bow, while others were clearly left in a big, knotted mess for next season. Of course, spoilers galore. I’m just hoping I can keep track of them all. Olivia and the gladiators (someone needs to create a retro doo-wop band with that title) spend a considerable amount of time trying to unravel the whole Cytron card mess. In short, they discover what we already knew (David Rosen!) plus some. While David seems to be an evil little snitch initially, and apparently has somewhere else to be while the gladiators close in on his nefarious doings, we soon learn that this terrible plot is actually happiness and light at the end of the day. David wasn’t a “bad” guy (I use quotations, because logically it would not be a bad thing for him to seek revenge on Olivia and her gang for all the crappy things they did to him), he was a gladiator, too.

            Even though he managed to get a full confession out of Billy Chambers for killing Wendy and Molly and “the CIA guy” (Chambers is so murder-y, he can barely keep track of them all!), it was all part of his plan. I guess Quinn didn’t need to jam a drill into Chambers after all, because David had never given him the Cytron card in the first place. Instead, he taped his confession, hands the card over to Cyrus (who had already had to listen to Hollis demand he get the “bang bang, boohoo, bye-bye” treatment) and asks for one little thing in exchange. Next thing you know, Fitz is naming David to be the District Attorney for Washington D.C. I’ll be sad not to see him hanging around Olivia’s office like a grumpy college student or recently divorced guy, but I’m sure he’ll be more fun in an actual position of power. Sidebar: Just wondering if anyone’s going to do something to Governor Restin. Sure, he didn’t play a major role in the scheme to blackmail Fitz, but I’m thinking someone’s going to give him a rap on the knuckles.
            
            Still, I have to say I didn’t disagree with “bad” David. Olivia and her people had ruined his life and essentially revved up the car, run over him, backed up, then run over him again. I think it’s probably a good thing that the season is ending now, because I’ll have time to think about how screwed up it is to root for a president that kills people, his mistress who looks the other way when people are tortured and helped to fix an election, and her devoted minions who do all sorts of nefarious things in the belief that they’re on the right side. I mean, it makes you not want to vote, ever.
            
            At first, we think that Defiance is now done, done, done, and all the President needs to do is run again, dump Mellie, and marry Olivia. Easy peasy! Yeah, someone tries to kill Oliviaand stuff, so that makes you think it may not be so easy. Jake comes to her rescue, because he’s just That Guy, and he informs her that he’s just a B-613 minion who slept with her because he had to, so there. Olivia knows he’s going to die for saving her life, and she wants to help. No, no! There’s no helping a B-613 guy! Poor Jake must simply walk away, knowing he’s saved the pretty girl he can never have. It’s very sad, at least until we see he isn’t killed and is instead just dumped in that horrible hole Huck was one stuck into. I’m a little sad for the girl Jake killed, but I guess we’re not supposed to talk about that. One thing that I think all of us saw coming weeks ago and were just wondering why it hadn’t happened yet (and you can almost never say that about this show) is that Cyrus had a heart attack. It was a relief to see nothing can kill this guy, though I thought Olivia just might do it when she calmly explained to him that she and Fitz are going to get married and tra-la-la into the sunset. “What, you thought the black ops guys were firing heart shaped bullets?” he screeches. When her response to Cyrus is that he’s being dramatic, he hits his sputtering, apoplectic high points. “Romeo and Juliette were teenagers and they died!”
              </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="8">
        <name>Good Trouble</name>
        <title>'Good Trouble': How the Freeform Drama Puts a New Spin on 'The Fosters'</title>
        <image>
            https://nypdecider.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/good-trouble-149651_9246.jpg
        </image>
        <review>Good Trouble is what happens when a teen drama transmogrifies into a workplace dramedy — moments of youthful levity between friends become bogged down by triggeringly realistic scenes of professional peril. I appreciate that this show depicts a clerkship for once, instead of another litigious white-shoe firm. But when Callie becomes embroiled in a ripped-from-the-headlines Black Lives Matter case, I bristled at the surface-deep social justice angle, which comes across more as pandering fan service to a left-leaning audience than as an nuanced exploration of a real-life human rights issue. Mariana's storyline fares better, the details of her workplace harassment feeling akin to a blistering Silicon Valley exposé, but I found myself dreading any scenes set at their respective offices, unwilling to accept from my entertainment what I could skim on my Newsfeed. I just wanted them to get back to their fun little commune and hang out with all their new alternative friends.

            The women's shabby-chic art deco home setting, the Coterie, is where this show really thrives. The Adams Fosters sisters fit right in with a diverse array of twenty-something artists, hipsters and influencers, including, among others: Alice (Sherry Cola), a down-to-earth Asian-American lesbian still in love with her demanding ex; Gael (Tommy Martinez), a brooding bisexual graphic artist and sculptor; and Davya (Emma Hunton), a brash plus-size social media guru unhappy at her Teach for America gig. When the show allows these young folks to just live in their uncertainty without artificially dangling them into sociopolitical relevancy, it shines. The episode where Alice struggles with her commitment as the commune's house manager (while generously buying toilet paper for everyone out of her own pocket) rings far truer than an idealistic former teenage convict trying to fight the good fight through lawyerly benevolence. The best episode of the five I watched sees Callie and Mariana's earnest moms (The Fosters' Sherri Saum and Teri Polo) visit the Coterie and experience all its weirdness within, including accidentally ingesting potent edibles and taking part in a wacky improv performance. It's a lot more fun to sit through than a schmaltzy, half-baked legal plotline.
            
            Keep that in mind, for as girl-power zippy as this show is, it's a bit of a cognitive exercise to get through. (Given pilot director John M. Chiu's dizzying camera and jumpy editing, I wouldn't recommend this is a background show.) The scripts consistently play with time, a jarring effect that makes your brain work harder than it should have to for something this glossy. In fact, the show's frequent flashbacks, cut-tos and in media res framing devices more than once gave me a Family Guy vibe. Bless this stress.
        </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="9">
        <name>Silicon Valley</name>
        <title>“Silicon Valley” Make For Best Comedy Hour on TV</title>
        <image>
            https://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/blog_post/primary_image/streaming/hbos-brilliant-veep-and-silicon-valley-make-for-best-comedy-hour-on-tv/silicon15_02.jpg
        </image>
        <review>The night starts with “Silicon Valley”, which picks up shortly after the end of last season (which was just released on Blu-ray and DVD, by the way, along with the third season of “Veep”, for those of you who need to catch up or like to collect your favorite shows). Pied Piper just blew everybody’s mind at the Techcrunch: Disrupt presentation, leading to dozens of bids to invest in their compression software. Life is good for the boys, but fortunes are quickly reversed by two major events. First, their investor, Peter Gregory, passes away, as Judge and his team needed to write the real-life passing of Christopher Evan Welch into their series. Losing Gregory (and the explanation of his death really is one of the best scenes in the series yet, turning real tragedy into something hysterical) forces the Pied Piper gang to look elsewhere for the bulk of their funding, a decision that leaves them totally adrift when Hooli gets back in their business.

            “Silicon Valley” has become a show about the intersection of intellectualism and male relationships. The guys of the Pied Piper group are undeniably brilliant, and yet they’re young enough to do childish things to one another and get fascinated by an app that just texts the word “bro” to other people. They are a modern take on “Revenge of the Nerds” if the characters in that movie were also eventual millionaires. Judge captures how these socially awkward creatures have become some of the most important and popular people in the world. But that doesn’t mean they know how to swing a bat or talk to girls. And even the successful ones are socially stunted. Chris Diamontopoulos is a fantastic addition this season as a multi-millionaire who lucked into his tech fortune and now wields it like a frat boy who won the lottery.
            
            The cast of “Silicon Valley” was great last season, but they’re much more confident this season in the three episodes that were sent to press. Thomas Middleditch and T.J. Miller have a few scenes in the premiere in which they try to reverse-“neg” their competition that had me laughing out loud, while Martin Starr and Kumail Nanjiani have developed a reluctant friendship comedic chemistry that’s just perfect. There’s sort of a “fill-in” character for Gregory this season on whom I’m not yet sold after three episodes, but the saga of Pied Piper still promises to be one of the most interesting, and hysterical ones of the Spring.
         </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="10">
        <name>Jack Ryan</name>
        <title>An American Hero Returns in Thrilling New Series, Tom Clancy's Jack Ryan</title>
        <image>
            https://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/blog_post/primary_image/streaming/an-american-hero-returns-in-thrilling-new-series-tom-clancys-jack-ryan/Jack-Ryan-image.jpg
        </image>
        <review>Those who tune into Amazon’s new series “Tom Clancy’s Jack Ryan” are in for a big surprise, in more ways than one. First, its vision of international espionage proves that thrilling action storytelling doesn’t require gun lust, motorcycle chases, or brashness with death to hold a tight grip. Even more, the series is packaged like the sharper version of a Paul Haggis movie, illustrating the various sides to its conflict, reckoning that terrorism is a tragedy more complicated than one-dimensional villainy. Expertly plotted by creators Carlton Cuse and Graham Roland, “Tom Clancy’s Jack Ryan” is all the more impactful for its restraint and scope, offering excellent character-based drama that’s concerned with much more than just its namesake.

            The poster boy for this exciting, sensitive take to worldly anxieties is John Krasinski, who continues to ascend as our current contemplating everyman, coming off the artistic rejuvenation of nervously glancing and not speaking in “A Quiet Place.” His take on Jack Ryan, very much his own after the character has been played by Alec Baldwin, Harrison Ford, Ben Affleck and Chris Pine, is a financial analyst with a military past, but a nervous rookie when it comes to preventing global terrorism. In the six episodes offered to critics (of the eight total available on Friday), I hardly saw him fire a gun, but I watched him do a whole lot of thinking.
            
            In a thrilling opening episode directed by Morten Tyldum ("The Intimidation Game"), Ryan is thrown into the mix when he starts tracking multimillion dollar payments abroad made to a suspicious account. Suddenly, the man with a doctorate in economics is now in Yemen to help interrogate a suspect named Suleiman, about money that could have leads to the next Bin Laden (“9/11” and “Bin Laden” are admittedly referenced with such weight in these moments that the button-pushing just becomes goofy.) Nevertheless, this pilot is a great display of how Krasinski can involve us in his characters’ quiet calculation of the information around him, but also in his anxiousness concerning the unpredictable. The series in turn doesn’t try to tell us that he’s not scared when dodging gunfire during the pilot’s explosive climax, or uncomfortable when negotiating with shady characters. It all does wonders for slowly, believably pushing his reinvented character out of the office, with Jack feeling as vulnerable as the story itself feels alive. It’s a steady build for this character, but for like much of this compulsively watchable series, proves to be incredibly rewarding.
            
            The closest that “Tom Clancy’s Jack Ryan” has to a “classic” macho hero is in Wendell Pierce’s James Greer, Ryan’s no-BS boss. And even then, he’s not a typical construct: Greer's a former key player in the CIA who was damned to a desk after an incident he won’t talk about, and he’s a Muslim. Leading with cutting wisdom and unblinking certainty, Pierce makes for a sturdy opposite to Ryan and a good companion; it’s very funny, too when Pierce rips on Ryan’s brainy aspect, irritatingly calling the titular hero “Peabody.” Together, the two are a formidable home base for the story’s American side.
         </review>
    </serie>
    <serie id="11">
        <name>The morning show</name>
        <title>Apple TV Plus’ The Morning Show Offers A-List Cast But Little Else</title>
        <image>
            ttps://static.rogerebert.com/redactor_assets/pictures/5db74222646d6a590846d5c7/content_the_morning_show_JA_RW.jpg
        </image>
        <review>Apple TV’s mega-budget, star-studded flagship series “The Morning Show” wants to be the “House of Cards” for the fledgling streaming service. It wants to be the program that puts Apple TV Plus on the map, critically and commercially. Unless something drastically changes after episode three, the last one sent to press for review, this feels unlikely to happen. Oh, people will tune in for the star power alone, but a long, complex production process has left this show in search of an identity. Not unlike actual TV journalism in the late ‘10s, “The Morning Show” can’t quite figure what it wants to be, waffling between a soapy take on super personalities like “All About Eve” and “serious” commentary on the state of the world like “The Newsroom.” A couple of the performances—and one in particular—keep it from being a complete disaster, but the show has a high degree of unearned self-importance.

            A tumultuous production process is evident right from the beginning of “The Morning Show” in a pilot that can’t find its tone or story. Development for this show began about two years ago, before the #MeToo and #FakeNews movements had gained as much cultural relevance as they would over the course of production. Consequently, a show that was reportedly developed as an expose on journalism created by “House of Cards” producer Jay Carson had to become something else to reflect the era in which it was made. Carson left the show, replaced by Kerry Ehrin (“Bates Motel”), and the story of “The Morning Show” shifted, although arguably not enough. It feels caught between a frothy look at TV news politics and a sharp commentary on the state of journalism, too often failing to be either.
            
            One of the interesting undercurrents of “The Morning Show” that’s a bit underdeveloped is the idea that scandal creates opportunity. Every position emptied by a #MeToo controversy has been filled by someone else. One person’s worst day is another’s chance to climb the ladder. And this is especially true in the world of journalism, one in which reporting on awfulness can often make your career. It certainly seems like the event that opens “The Morning Show” could do that for two people—veteran Alex Levy (Jennifer Aniston) and newcomer Bradley Jackson (Reese Witherspoon). Alex has co-hosted a successful but sagging morning news show a la “Today” or “Good Morning America” with Mitch Kessler (Steve Carell), who gets hit with the accusations of sexual impropriety in the premiere. Exactly what Mitch did remains frustratingly unclear—he claims he just had affairs, and everyone seems to agree that terms like rape or assault aren’t appropriate—but he’s guilty in the court of public opinion and immediately fired. Alex has to go on-air alone and strike the right tone, which she absolutely does. As the new head of news Cory Ellison (Billy Crudup) says, “It’s too bad we can’t always throw crisis at her—it turns her lights on.”
            
            You see, Cory and others were planning to push Alex out, delaying her new contract, but now they may be stuck with her as firing Mitch’s partner in the wake of a #MeToo scandal would look bad. Cory finds a way to shake things up with the discovery of a fiery reporter (Witherspoon’s Bradley) in a video rant at a coal miner’s strike goes viral. Of course, Bradley is the opposite of Alex in many ways, and has zero anchor experience. You can probably see where this battle of wills is going ... very slowly. Mark Duplass, Gugu Mbatha-Raw, Nestor Carbonell, Bel Powley, and Desean K. Terry fill out an undeniably stacked supporting cast.
         </review>
    </serie>
</series>